Guide to the Records of Office of Radio and Television RG 7.3.1
New York University Archives
- Series II: Subject Files, 1953-1980
  - Subseries B: Subject Files
    - Public Service Announcements Mailing List, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - The Radiation Story, 1962-1963 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - The Radiation Story, 1962-1969 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Rourke, Ralph, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Survival in the City, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - The 21st Century: Threshold, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - The 21st Century: Threshold, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - The 21st Century: Threshold, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - The 21st Century: Threshold, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - University Broadcast Lab, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - University Broadcast Lab, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "University", 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "University", undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "University", undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "University", 1959 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - "University", 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - "University", 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - The Urban Crisis Clinic, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - The Urban Crisis Clinic, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - The Urban Crisis Clinic, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - The Urban Crisis Clinic, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - "The Urbanites" Partnership for Excellence, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - "The Urbanites" Partnership for Excellence, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Weeks, Albert L., Troubled Détente, 1976-1978 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Weeks, Albert L., 1965-1973 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Wisdom Bank, 1969-1972 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Wisdom Bank, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Wisdom Bank, 1969-1972 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Wisdom Bank, 1971-1973 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Wisdom Bank, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - "Youth Forum", 1962 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - "You've Got A Right", 1964 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Loose Documents, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Subseries C: Subject Files, 1962-1979
    The bulk of these records consists of correspondence, primarily of Ralph Rourke, then the Assistant to the Director of Radio & Television, show scripts, program formats, budgets news clippings and press releases. These records reflect program management activities. They are primarily concerned with program funding and research, guest lists, guest questions, public relations, program scheduling and production. This series illustrates both the educational and even more important the public relations aspects of the office. Shows such as "Soul of Reason" and "Black Depths" examined topical aspects of black life, culture, politics and history. Shows like "Stock Market Observer" and "Taxpayers Clinic" provided the general viewing public with financial and investment information as well as forthcoming income tax filing changes.
    Minutes from meetings of the University Television Committee, committee member names, early proposals and funding tactics are included here. The materials also document the University Broadcast Lab series. This was a highly successful endeavor which aired on WNYC-TV Channel 31 on Sundays from 6:00 to 6:30 am. In this series NYU students directed produced and performed in various productions. Included here are script samples, directors' kits and make-up techniques. The materials also document the NYU weekly radio show "Sound of Science," which first aired on WRCA on February 19, 1958. An early production of the office of Radio and Television, the show sought to promote the recognition and encouragement of scientific talent.
    - Educational Television, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Meet The Professor, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Sawhill - Broadcast, 1975-1979 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Sawhill - Corresp, 1975-1979 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Sawhill - NYU Faculty, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Sawhill - NY State, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Sawhill - Press, 1975-1979 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - School of Arts/Metromedia Project, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Sonic Boom Study, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Sound Of Science - Press, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Sound of Science - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Soul Of Reason - Prospectus, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Soul Of Reason - Program Schedule, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Soul Of Reason - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Soul Of Reason - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Soul Of Reason - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Soul Of Reason - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Soul Of Reason - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Market Observer, 1968-1969 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Survival In The City Prospectus, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Survival In The City Budget, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Survival In The City Press Relations, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Survival In The City Correspondence, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Survival In The City Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Survival In The City Programs 1-8, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Survival In The City Programs 9-13, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Survival In The City Programs 14-16, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Survival In The City Programs 17-20, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Taxpayers Clinic, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Television Committee Correspondence, 1958-1961 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - This is Wall Street Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - This is Wall Street Stock Quotes, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - This is Wall Street Stock Quotes, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Newsletter, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Tomorrow - WHN Project, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Town Hall, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Wall Street Final, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - University Background, 1973-1978 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Floor plans, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Petty Cash, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Programs, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Programs, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Petty Cash, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Dunbar, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Scripts, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Scripts, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Students, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Students, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - University Broadcast Labs - Make-up, 1970-1971 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - University Broadcast Labs - News, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - University Broadcast Labs - News, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - University Challenge, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Press Conference, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Subseries D: Press Office Subject Files, 1976-1982
    This subseries consists general office files from the NYU Press Office from 1976-1982. These are subject files arranged in chronological order, earliest year first, with documents in each folder arranged in the same fashion. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence, memos, press releases, drawing and diagrams, maps and charts, plans and blueprints. This series deals with the administrative and functional aspects of the NYU Office Of Public Affairs. Items include day to day activities of the office such as moves, equipment and furniture requirements, telephone needs, fire and safety issues. This series also illustrates the importance of the Office Of Public Affairs in terms of input to the annual report, commencement exercises and university advertising campaigns. For example, the materials document the Chet Huntley Memorial Lecture Series. This annual program was a joint venture between NYU, NBC News and the advertising firm of Levin, Huntley and Schmidt. A committee headed by Dr. Sawhill and NBC news correspondent John Chancellor selected the speakers for the annual event. Other materials document the 1981 and 1982 NYU Commencement Exercises. Included here are the president's remarks to the graduating class, the trustees dinner ceremony, press releases on the event and the commencement exercises program itself.
    - Labor Relations, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Public Affairs Christmas Party, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Chet Huntley Memorial, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Organization Charts, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Thomas Cooke, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Public Affairs Move (Corresp), 1979-1980 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Public Affairs Move (Floor Plns), 1979-1980 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Public Affairs Move (Furn/Equip), 1979-1980 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - University Facilities (Guidelines), 1979 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Public Affairs Christmas Party, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Annual Report (Corresp), 1980 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Annual Report (Pres Letter), 1980-1981 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Fumes, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Memberships, Institutional, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - NYU Distribution Report, 1980-1981 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Public Affairs Christmas Party, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Safety Committee, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Advertising Advisory Committee, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - American Council on Education, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Association for a Better New York, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Careers in Business, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Commencement (Presidential Remarks), 1981 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Commencement (Trustees), 1981 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Commencement (Press Release), 1981 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Commencement (Program), 1981 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Leadership Campaign, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Directory - 25 - West 4th Street, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Dr. John Brademas, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Founders Day, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Black Faculty and Administration, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Commencement (Presidential Remarks), 1982 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Commencement (Trustees), 1982 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Commencement (Press Release), 1982 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Commencement (Program), 1982 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Public Affairs Christmas Party, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Report: NYU Print Shop, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 19)